XUE PAVILION
It's ready.
Made with what we procured, is it?
It's made with the gold we procured.
I watched him the whole time.
Second Master, four cun, as ordered.
It'll be easy for a child to handle.
However, Young Master is still very young.
Should we give him something this sharp?
Why not?
I was already
slaughtering sheep when I was his age.
The young master of the Huben Army
will lead the army in the future.
He has to prove himself capable.
Don't tell my brother.
-Huai'an!
Regarding this matter,
I can only
rely on you.
All right.
I'll do it on your behalf.
You must hang in there.
Please hang in there.
Huai'an.
Please hang in there!
Huai'an?
-Huai'an.
-Xie Huai'an.
-Hang in there.
Where is the physician?
Xiaoqing's gone to notify him.
He'll be here soon.
Why did she go to notify him?
Just bring him here!
Huai'an?
Brother.
Hurry!
Prepare the anti-bleeding decoction.
I'll pull out the sword.
You, help me stop the bleeding.
Okay.
Can you do this?
I cannot.
Go away.
Don't stare at me. If he can't do it,
-I can't do it.
-Useless fools.
I'll do it.
He'll bleed a lot.
I'm not afraid.
Hang in there.
I rushed here upon hearing
that Mr. Xie was attacked.
What's the current situation?
How is Mr. Xie doing?
Guys,
why are you all keeping quiet?
Please tell me something.
This…
You want me to head back?
I…
How am I supposed to report back?
It's all my fault.
This wouldn't have happened
had I not failed
to deliver the letter back then.
I was at the entrance just now.
I didn't dare to enter.
I was afraid that he might…
In his letter, he stated
that he would spend the rest of his life
avenging his family.
He was ready for a life like this.
He won't blame anyone
even if he dies in the process.
Don't be afraid.
Huai'an won't fall yet.
Young Master!
The Young Master is here.
Young Master.
Uncle!
Uncle! Father is still alive!
Hurry and find a physician!
Father. Please don't die.
Father!
Don't leave me!
Father?
Where are we?
It was Uncle!
Uncle rescued us!
Protect your sister.
You two
must live on.
Father!
Protect your sister.
You two must live on.
Father…
Master.
I know what you guys are trying to ask.
You see…
I don't know.
What do you mean?
He won't die if he manages
to regain consciousness.
That sounds ominous.
What if he doesn't?
Great question.
His injuries are too grievous.
He has lost too much blood.
He might not wake up again.
I already fed him
the medicine I prescribed.
At least his heart can keep beating.
If he doesn't regain consciousness,
he will age very slowly.
By the time we die,
grow old or turn to ashes,
his hair might only just have turned gray.
Does that mean
he'll be in an eternal coma?
You could say so.
He will regain consciousness.
He begged me for a favor
before he fainted.
I know.
There are many things
he has yet to accomplish.
A person like him,
if he has any unfulfilled wishes,
he will surely wake and fulfill them.
Xiaoqing,
the messenger under you is being targeted.
You are being targeted as well.
Let's investigate the case together.
I've worn this charm
as long as I can remember.
Although I've faced many trials,
it did keep me safe until now.
I'll hand it to you.
May you overcome this ordeal.
What does this mean?
The general sent us a letter.
He said you made a mistake.
I want to know
what Yan Fengshan deemed my mistake to be.
When the city fell, your subordinates,
they failed to capture
the deposed emperor.
That was one of your mistakes.
Now that your nephew
has the deposed emperor with him,
there's no way he can be killed off.
You disobeyed the general's order.
Not only did you intervene personally,
but you also mobilized
many of our men without permission.
You completely lost sight
of the bigger picture.
And, Qingyi died because of you.
That was your second mistake.
There's no place for you
in Hidden Soldier Alley anymore.
After him!
Give it to me.
-Just let him play with it.
-Give it to me!
Give it to him.
Give it to me!
Here you go.
Sir, you're seriously wounded.
I didn't dare hire a physician.
I only used the Liu family's
anti-bleeding mix on you.
I was fortunate.
I'm still alive.
Xingzi,
since when did you get yourself a family?
I'm a single man in my thirties.
I was not careful with my coin
when I had some.
Speaking of which,
Sir, you have rarely visited me
all these years.
I never thought I'd see you wounded.
So,
is there anything I can do for you?
Where's your carriage?
I have one.
I keep it
at the marketplace's carriage house.
Can I leave the city in it?
You can. It's fully licensed.
Take me out of the city.
Sir,
I saw that you had a travel pass with you
when I was dressing your wound.
Must I go with you?
Right now,
you're the only person I can trust.
Back then, you joined hands with me
to strike down my brother.
Back then, I…
I merely struck him down
as proof of my loyalty, Sir.
I did it so that I could survive.
Poor people like us
do everything we can to survive.
If you wish to survive,
you have to follow my command.
It is not as though I will harm you.
Am I right?
I'll go and get the carriage.
-It'll take two or three days.
-You have two.
In two days, at sunset,
in the alley west of Yanping Gate,
I'll wait for you there.
Okay.
Xingzi.
Once you've done me this favor,
we shall be even.
We won't see each other again
after I leave the city.
Thank you, sir.
You're chopping firewood at night.
Don't you think it's noisy?
What's wrong?
I was just trying to help her out.
Besides, it's not as if we're
in a stranger's house.
This is Miss Bai Wan's residence.
I'm chopping firewood for her.
What has that to do
with Miss Bai Wan herself?
You were being noisy
by chopping firewood at night.
What I meant was,
Miss Bai Wan was far calmer than we were
when the physician was
pulling the sword from Xie Huai'an.
Now, he needs people to tend to him.
And Miss Bai Wan is
more meticulous than we are.
So I thought
I'd at least chop firewood to help them.
Unlike you, who only stand here
like a statue.
Say,
what's the relationship
between Bai Wan and Xie Huai'an?
That has nothing to do with you.
You should rest early.
You have to take over my shift tomorrow.
Of course it has nothing to do with me.
I know I've fallen from grace.
But back then,
I was a member of the imperial family.
Within the Capital,
among the high-ranking noble families,
I know every matter
related to them, big or small.
I even witnessed some of them.
For example,
Xie Huai'an has a younger sister.
When his sister turned a year old,
she received a birthday gift
that was very eye-catching.
It was a Hard Bamboo Carved Amulet.
And, I saw it last night.
Hey, lower your voice.
What are you saying?
The siblings have been reunited.
Isn't that great?
What are you doing? It's spilling!
That was hot!
Listen.
You'd better keep this to yourself.
If you tell anyone about it,
I'll break your legs.
Huai'an doesn't want her to know
that she's a member of the Liu family.
He said every member
of the Liu family was ill-fated.
Indeed.
And, they don't live long either.
If he doesn't make it this time…
If he passes…
I'll have to flee again.
Don't worry.
If anything happens to Huai'an,
I'll drag you down with him.
What has this got to do with me?
It's because you're a jinx.
He'll be fine.
Grand Preceptor already said
that he could live until the age of 83.
Grand Preceptor? Which one?
The one who was in power when
my father was the emperor, Cen Weizong.
Cen Weizong?
He's a renowned fortune-teller.
That's why I said
his prediction will be accurate.
When did he have his fortune told?
It was when…
Ten…
I think when he was 12.
Huai'an was on the run when he was 12.
He wouldn't have had time
for a fortune reading.
Grand Preceptor told my fortune
when I was 12.
He said I could live until the age of 83.
How could I live until 83
without Xie Huai'an's protection?
If I do live until 83,
doesn't that mean he'll be protecting me
until he's 83?
That's why
Xie Huai'an can live until 83 as well.
Don't worry about it.
Here.
So bitter.
I'll accomplish
the task you assigned once it's dawn.
But I have limited capabilities.
Your revenge must be taken step by step.
If you want full revenge,
you have to wake up
and do it yourself.
What are you staring at?
There's only one bowl here.
I cannot believe she keeps
only one bowl and one teacup in her house.
Is he okay?
He's fine. He's still unconscious.
I have something to do outside.
You're leaving at this moment?
Xiaoqing told me what happened.
Huben attacked you guys out of the blue.
And, there was a huge commotion.
I'm sure security in the city
will be tightened.
They will not dare strike again.
If you're still worried,
tell Commander Wang
to post men here in secret.
It'll be fine.
Okay.
Please go ahead.
I'll keep an eye on him.
You can have the noodles.
Why don't you have them?
Really?
It smells great.
In the future, you can be my book-boy.
Or my cook, perhaps.
Miss, come and take a look.
Look at all the varieties.
-Let's take a look.
-Please take a look.
-Fine goods for sale.
-What do you think?
-How much?
-This one?
It suits you. You can have it for one wen.
-It's raining!
-Let's go! Let's go!
The rain came out of nowhere.
-Let's hurry.
-It's raining. Let's hurry!
‎-Quick, get out of the way.
‎-Hurry up.
Let's seek shelter under the roof.
‎-It's starting to rain.
‎-Come on, move.
Please come again tomorrow.
-Come back tomorrow, sir.
-Let's go, let's go.
These ornaments are exquisite.
I wish to buy some after the rain stops.
Sure. Thank you.
‎Get under cover for a bit.
You’re drenched.
‎-You all right?
‎-Same here.
Miss, you've truly done me a huge favor.
These accessories aren't made
with gold or jade.
I wouldn't be able to sell them out
if they were drenched.
Don't mention it.
From your accent,
I'd say you're not from Chang'an.
I'm not that lucky.
Both my husband and I came from Huzhou.
We run a small trade
to make a living in Chang'an.
In Chang'an, food is costly.
Rent is worse.
It's tough to live here.
Since that's the case,
why didn't you return to Huzhou?
I've tried to persuade my husband
for many years.
But he always told me
that we should give it more time.
He kept saying that.
And now,
our daughter is already 6 years old.
Even so, he still won't leave.
I wonder why.
Miss, what about you?
You owe a blood debt.
That is why you cannot leave.
Miss, what do you mean?
My daughter's bangle.
Why do you have it with you?
Tell your husband this.
It's time for him to clear the debt
he owed 15 years ago.
Your daughter will return to you
once he does so.
It doesn't seem like
the rain will stop anytime soon.
Father.
Are you cold?
Yes.
If this keeps up,
you won't be able to survive.
But Father, I lost you.
At first,
I could've saved you.
I don't want to live anymore.
Whenever you face this moment,
you have to find a reason to live.
I took my sister
out of the Grand Preceptor's Residence.
We left Chang'an.
We walked 70 li.
And, we arrived at Nanwei Trough.
It was too cold.
We were starving.
I couldn't walk anymore.
In the town,
there wasn't a single oil lamp.
There was no fire at all.
But my sister and I…
we wanted to have some hot soup.
I hid her
in a thatched hut by the roadside.
And, I left.
When I found some food
and returned to the hut,
my sister
had already been taken in
by a kind-hearted soul.
She was so young.
She wouldn't have survived
had she stayed with me.
Perhaps she would be able
to grow up safely
if she weren't a member of the Liu family.
After that,
I hid among the reeds of Nanwei Trough
and sustained myself for seven years
as I watched over her.
Her foster family
treated her kindly.
You've already done a great job.
Can you still go on?
I… I'm so worn out.
Why don't you hang on for a little longer?
Until the next blooming season?
I just think
that my son
deserves to see the flowers bloom again.
After the blooming season,
you can wait just a little longer.
Once the petals fall
and the July rains pass,
you can wait just a little longer.
You can wait until your wife
sets a meal before you.
Just lead a peaceful life
as you keep on waiting.
On the surface,
it seems a good life.
It is a life of merely getting by.
Father, your hands are so cold.
You were hunted down.
No matter how I tried to catch up,
I could never catch up to that carriage.
-Father!
-I could only stare.
You were stabbed many times.
-There was blood everywhere.
-Father!
That was my last image of you.
As a son,
from now on,
I merely live
to avenge you.
I don't want you living like this.
But I want to.
Even if I have to sacrifice everything,
I won't hesitate at all.
Revenge…
-Revenge…
-What am I to do if you never wake?
Don't tell me you're already…
Keep talking like that
and you'd better leave.
Revenge…
I think he talked just now.
Come here.
What did he say?
I think he's trying to say
that he wants to find
his mother.
Water.
Water?
-He wants water. Hurry.
-I'll go and get some.
How is he? Has he regained consciousness?
-He talked just now.
-Yeah.
He said he wanted to find his mother.
He also said he wanted some water.
I want to seek revenge.
He's saying
that he wants revenge.
Huai'an?
-Huai'an, you're awake.
-Huai'an?
Finally, my bodyguard is awake.
How long was I out?
Two days.
Be careful.
Regarding the task I told you…
Don't worry about it.
Everything has been arranged.
He hasn't left the city.
Good.
He hasn't left the city, huh?
That means I still stand a chance
to hunt him down.
Hunt him down?
Hunt who?
Liu Ziyan.
He does not deserve to draw breath.
Sir.
All three divinations forebode misfortune.
You're leaving the city at this hour?
I'm on an errand
for the Peacekeeper Corps.
Sir, I have no choice either.
This is the official letter
and travel pass.
You may pass.
Thank you, sir.
Hurry!
I've been getting by
in Chang'an for many years.
In the end, I still
have to leave this city.
What is it?
The carriage hit a rock.
It's dark out.
Be careful.
If I die now,
you'll never learn
what your father
told me
before he died.
It doesn't matter.
That no longer matters to me.
Young Master!
I had no choice either back then.
If I didn't help him out,
I would've been dead!
If I didn't stab your father,
my parents would've been killed!
I was selfish. I was a coward.
I deserve to die!
But you see,
my daughter is innocent in all this.
You can do whatever you want to me.
But please spare my daughter!
FAIR DEALS FOR ALL
NEW FORTUNE, LONG LIFE
You've settled your debt.
You may reunite with your family.
Young Master, thank you!
Young Master, thank you
for your great kindness!
Thank you so much!
My dear girl.
Hurry. Greet your father.
-Father.
-Let me carry you.
Father, you're drenched.
I'm fine.
Let me dry you.
I thought you would kill him.
I'm different from those people.
Let's go.
Let's head home.
Okay. Let's head home.
DAHUANG
LIU ZIWEN
On the 7th day of the 12th month,
in the 17th year of Qiansheng,
we encountered the body
of General Liu Ziwen along the road.
Our hearts were heavy with grief.
We, mere commoners,
respecting the name
and virtue of the General,
pooled our efforts
to give him a proper burial here.
We performed the rites
on behalf of future generations,
placed him in his coffin,
and interred him in his tomb,
so as to comfort
the heroic spirit of the General.
Father.
So, you were here all along.
The city of Chang'an
has never forgotten about you.
Father.
I'm still alive.
My sister is alive as well.